Mss.B.M58.1
American Philosophical Society
Francois André Michaux papers, 1802-1911
Mss.B.M58.1
American Philosophical Society
0.25 Linear feet Ca. 300 items
Relating especially to American Philosophical Society business, these papers contain letters to and from men of science and institutions in Europe on the purchase and shipment of books and on the pubications of the Society. Many of the letters are to or from John Vaughan.
Ca. 300 items.
Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
Box 1
Scope and Contents note
This collection contains about 340 items that relate to François Andre Michaux, his work, and the legacy he left to the APS. The items are dated between 1802 and 1911. The material is in English and French. A typed table of contents is included in the box.
The majority of the letters are about Michaux’s relationship with the American Philosophical Society. A large number of items consist of letters by Michaux to John Vaughan, secretary, treasurer and librarian of the APS. Most of these letters, which are in French, cover shipments of books and other publications from Michaux to the APS. Included are, for example, lists of books requested by the APS and lists of books that Michaux sent to the APS.
Items that shed light on the American editions of Michaux’s work includes his detailed instructions to whomever decided to publish his Sylva in the United States (1 September 1810), as well as a letter by Obadiah Rich to Vaughan, in which Rich inquires about plans to publish a translation of Michaux’s work on forest trees. The letter is written on a printed proposal for the printing of Arator by John Taylor (12 March 1814).
Another body of items deals with Michaux’s testament and his legacy to the APS. Many of these items are addressed from or to Charles Trego, the Society's secretary. Of particular interest are Michaux’s will (4 September 1855) and extracts from the minutes (19 September 1856 to 3 May 1867) that chronicle the APS’s efforts to secure the bequest. There are also a number of legal and private communications regarding his legacy, including several from and to A. Germain, the notary charged with the execution of the will, and Mrs. Beziers, Michaux’s widow, who, along with her husband, sued for the recovery of the legacy. Also of interest are the letters to and from Hector Bossange and his son Gustave Bossange, the Society’s book agents who represented the interests of the APS in Paris. Frustrated by Germain’s support of veuve (widow) Michaux’s claims, the APS eventually turned to the Minister of Justice for help in the matter (May 1867). J. Peter Lesley ultimately recommended that the APS grant Hector Bossange full legal powers to pursue their interests (23 March 1868); however, the APS decided to give power of attorney to Auguste Carlier (1868). Carlier reported in 1869 that he had finally secured the legacy for the APS, and that Mrs. Beziers would receive an annual interest. He felt “happy to have thus succeeded in my debut as a Member of the Philosophical Society. If it is not a scientific, it is, at the least, a profitable one and that is something” (23 April 1869).
The material dated 1870 and later discuss the use of the legacy, including the naming of a grove in Fairmount Park in honor of Michaux, and the purchase of trees for the park. Statements of accounts paid to the commissioners of Fairmount Park are also included (January 1872 to November 1888). Some of the proceeds from the Michaux legacy were also used to fund lectures on forestry by Joseph Rothrock, professor of biology at the University of Pennsylvania. Several items, including letters, receipts, and a list of lectures, shed light on the course, which was offered at the Franklin Institute.
Rothrock’s illustrations of the forest flora of the United States impressed the U.S. Department of Agriculture, which asked the APS to sponsor an exhibition of them at the Paris Exposition in 1889 (5 November 1888). The reluctance of the APS to contribute funds, on the grounds “that the Government, instead of asking assistance, should give aid,” are documented in several letters, including the letter from Fernow to Phillips (27 November 1888).
Early American History Note
The F.A. Michaux Collection is a large collection of correspondence. Francois Michaux was the son of Andre Michaux. He was, like his father, a botanist. Francois also was an active member of the APS. Michaux regularly corresponded with peers in Europe, and this collection captures the conveyance of news, information, and knowledge across the Atlantic. As an active member of the APS and other institutions, Michaux’s correspondence also lends insight into the establishment and operation of many scientific institutions. The vast majority of the collection consists of outgoing correspondence from Michaux; his primary correspondent was John Vaughan of the APS. The correspondence is almost exclusively in French. Later documents reflect the APS’s continued interest in silviculture, which was spurred by a bequest by Michaux. Included in this section is the APS’s acquisition of books and involvement in forest preservation and development, including the planting and preservation of Michaux Grove in Fairmount Park.
Related Archival Materials note
See also the Francois Andre Michaux Collection (Ms. Coll. 42) for photostat copies of Michaux-related documents from other repositories.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Assembled from the APS Archives and Misc. Ms. Collection; accessioned, 1958 (1958 2003ms). See in-house shelf list for additional accession numbers and dates.
Existence and Location of Copies note
This collection is also available on microfilm (Film 1412).
Biographical/Historical note
François André Michaux (1770-1855, APS 1809) was a French botanist, silviculturist, and explorer. With his father André he established and managed nurseries in Hackensack, N.J. and Charleston. S.C. His primary scientific contributions were more practical than his father’s. He described the properties and uses of various woods, plants, and soils. His major works were Voyage à l’Ouest des Monts Alléghanys (1804) and The North American Sylva; or, A Description of the Forest Trees... (1818-1819).
Michaux was born at Satory near Versailles, France, on August 16, 1770, the son of botanist André Michaux and his wife Cécile Claye. His mother died during childbirth. In 1785 he accompanied his father to the United States to establish a botanical nursery in Hackensack, N.J., where they grew trees for shipment to France. In 1787 he assumed primary responsibility for managing a second nursery near Charleston, S.C. Also in 1787 Michaux explored the Tennessee Valley, Florida and the Bahamas. In 1790 he returned to France to begin the study of medicine while participating in the French Revolution. Six years later in 1796 he helped his father to cultivate the plants brought back from America. In 1801 he returned to the United States under a commission from the French government to dismantle and sell the nurseries in Hackensack and Charleston. The following year he traveled from Philadelphia to Kentucky and Tennessee before returning to France in 1803. In 1806 he was back in the United States, collecting trees for France. In 1809 he explored the eastern states from Maine to Georgia and the Great Lakes. After returning to France, he prepared his monumental North American Sylva; he subsequently worked as the administrator of an experimental estate belonging to the Société Centrale de l’Agriculture.
Michaux, whose scientific endeavors were practical in nature, examined and described the characteristics and uses of various woods. He became a member of the American Philosophical Society in 1809 and received the Chevalier of the Legion of Honor. He married late in life and had no children. Michaux died on October 23, 1855.
American Philosophical Society.; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841; Fairmount Park (Philadelphia, Pa.); Foreign Language; Forests and forestry -- United States.; General Correspondence; Institutional Records; Science and Technology; Scientific Data
- Papers
  - Address to [Jacques Martin] Cels, June 20, 1802; 6-1/2x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Scope and Contents note
    A.D.S. 1p. and end. by J. Vaughan. In French.
  - Receipt for purchase of Michaux's work on American oak trees, July 29, 1802; 9-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: G. F. Favrey. 1p. and end.
  - Letter to Samuel Craft, July 29, 1806; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    A.L.S. 2p. add. In English. Mentions his travels, including his capture by a British vessel and transport to Bermudas and then Nova Scotia; was then allowed to return to the United States.
  - Letter to Samuel Craft, February 2, 1807; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Scope andf Contents note
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. add. In English. Travel plans in U.S. Troubles in New York; will send copy of "Travels" later. Concerning his plans to travel to the Carolinas and Georgia before going north to Massachusetts and New Hampshire. Includes a list of botanical questions he wants answered.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 29, 1809; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French. Business for the APS.
  - Letter to ----, April 27, 1809; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    In French.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 19, 1810; 10x7-3/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications to the APS. Refers to Warden, Barton, R. Patterson, and A. Wilson's American ornithology.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Aug. 19, 1810; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS, Barton, Wistar and Sully.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 20, 1810; 9x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Asks help on his book on American trees.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Aug. 21, 1810; 10x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L. 4p. Forwards part of his publication and sends instructions for their disposition.
  - Instructions to whomever would undertake an American edition of his Sylva..., Sept. 1, 1810; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    A.D.S. 4p. Refers to John Vaughan, Paul Sonnier, Marshall, and Z. Collins.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 7, 1810; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. In French. Recommends Borges of Portugual to him.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Sept. 17, 1810; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Concerning publications forwarded for the APS. Refers to Mease.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 27, 1810; 7-3/4x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Friendly letter. Warden leaves for the U.S.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Jan. 18, 1811; 9-1/2x7; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p., end. In French. Concerning publications and sends publications for the APS. Concerning his work. Refers to Wistar and R. M. Patterson
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 18, 1811; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    General note
    FILM 199 FRAME 690
    Paris, A.L.S. 6p., add. and end. Concerning publications sent to the APS Refers to Jefferson.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan?], Feb. 3, 1811; 9x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning publications and publications for the APS. Refers to R. M. Patterson, Warden, Wistar and Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 1, 1811; 9-1/2x7; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards Publication for the APS. Refers to R. M. Patterson and B. Vaughan.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 10, 1811; 9-1/2x7; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS. Refers to Wastar and Barton.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 18, 1811; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Mutilated. In French. Business.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], June 27, 1811; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L. 4p. In French. Has shipped publications for the APS. Refers to Barlow, Warden, Humboldt, Wistar and Maclure.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Dec. 3, 1811; 9x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    FILM 199 FRAME 691
    Paris, A.L.S. 5p. In French. Duplicate. Forwards publications. Refers to Jefferson.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 5, 1811; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. In French. Introduces Correa de Serra who he thinks would be a valuabe mamber to the APS.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Dec. 11, 1811; 8x6-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Lists plants to forward to Jamaica.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 17, 1811; 8-1/4x6-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forward publications. Refers to Warden.
  - Declaration of publications sent to John Vaughan for the American philosophical society, Jan. 27, 1812; 6-1/2x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S. 1p.
  - Bill of lading to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 15, 1812; 11-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S 2p., end In French. Publications for the APS, Wistar, Barton, Hosack, Biddle, Muhlenberg.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 11, 1812; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Orders copy of Wilson's ornithology. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 14, 1812; 8x6; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Wishes pass for APS journals.
  - Receipt to [François André] Michaux, June 23, 1812; 5x8; Muséum national d’histoire naturelle (France)
    Paris, Printed D. filled in in ms. S.: P. G. Dufor and Co. 1p. and end. by J. Vaughan. In French.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 2, 1812; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications to the APS. Refers to Humboldt and Wistar.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 23, 1812; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Current events. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 29, 1812; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, 1p. and add., end. In French. Concerning publications for the APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 14, 1813; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Ships publications. Refers to the APS Wistar, Humboldt, Correa de Serra and Hassler.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 7, 1813; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Ships publications to the APS. Refers to Hassler, Wistar and Bartram.
  - Bill of lading of publications shipped to the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia, Oct. 31, 1813; 8x6-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S. 1p. and add: John Vaughan, end.: Re"d by Thos W Roper. In French.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 12, 1814; 10x8; Rich, O., (Obadiah), 1777-1850
    Georgetown, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Inquires in re: Michaux's Sylva. Is printing Synopsis' of ... American Plants. On same sheet is: Taylor, John. ARATOR...[1814].
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 20, 1814; Roper, T. W.
    In English. Forwarding journals solicited by Michaux for the APS.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], July 1, 1814; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. In French. Forwards publications for the APS, Wistar, and others. Refers to Warden.
  - List of boxes sent to John Vaughan for the American Philosophical Society, July 18, 1814; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S. 1p. In French.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 20, 1814; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publication for the APS.
  - Letter to [François André] Michaux, Paris, Feb. 15, [1815]; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Grégoire, Henri, 1750-1831
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Friendly letter. Refers to Corea de Serra and Griffith.
  - Note to J[ohn] Vaughan, Dec. 18, 1814; 7-1/2x6; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    A.N.S. 1p. and end. In French. Donates book.
  - List of publications forwarded to John Vaughan, Feb., 1815; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    FILM 199 FRAME 692
    [received] A.D. 4p., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS, Z. Collins, Wistar, Maclure, Jefferson, etc.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan], Philadelphia, Feb. 23, 1815; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, 2p., add., end. In French. APS business.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 27, 1815; 9x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS. Attached to this letter is letter from same to same; April 28, 1815.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 28, 1815; 9x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS, Hassler and Z. Collins. Attached to letter from same to same; April 27, 1815.
  - Bill of lading to [John Vaughan] of books for the APS, May 1, 1815; 4x7-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S. 1p. In French. Attached to this is bill of lading from same to same; December 10, 1815.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 1, 1815; 9x7-3/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications. Refers to Z. Collins.
  - Letter to Samuel Bradford, May 5, 1815; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    In French. Regarding edition of his work. Plans to have a map of America complementing Humboldt’s map of Mexico.
  - Letter to Bernard MacMahon, Philadelphia, Aug. 23, 1815; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Concerning publications sent to J. Vaughan for the APS. Concerning Napoleon.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 23, 1815; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications. Concerning his work. Refers to Sully, Correa de Serra, and R. Patterson.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 14, 1815; 7-1/2x6; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications. Refers to Warden and Sully.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 19, 1815; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p., add., end. In French. Forwards publications. Refers to Hassler, Sully, and Humboldt.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Sept. 19-20, 1815; 10x8, 6x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 6p., end. In French. Forwards publication to the APS, Sully, Wistar and Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 6, 1815; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS. Refers to Hassler.
  - Letter to Benjamin Smith Barton, November 7, 1815; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    In English. Arranged for John Vaughan to deliver Barton two volumes of his work. Mentions bad political situation in France.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Dec. 3, 1815; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    A.L.S. 3p. and add. Mutilated. In French. Introduces Valli. Concerning APS business.
  - Bill of lading to John Vaughan of books for the APS, Dec. 10, 1815; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.D.S. 1P. and add., end. In French. Attached to bill of lading from same to same; May 1, 1815.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 10, 1815 - Jan. 7, 1816; 9-1/2x7-1/4 and 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS and Hassler. Refers to Wistar.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 27, 1815; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p, and add., end. In French. Forwards cases for Hassler and the APS. Refers to Warden, Gallatin and Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 30, 1815; 10x8-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications. Refers to Hassler, Wistar, Gallatin, and Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 22, 1816; 9-3/4x7-3/4; LeRoy, Bayard & Co. (New York, N.Y.).
    New York, L. 1p. and end. Concerning books from Michaux.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 2, 1816; 10x8; LeRoy, Bayard & Co. (New York, N.Y.).
    New York, L. 1p. and end. Concerning the expense of shipping books received from Michaux.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], April 25, 1816; 8-1/2x6-1/2, 2x6; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. Enc. of bill draw on John Vaughan; In French. Friendly letter. Shipped publications. Refers to Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 26, 1816; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS.
  - List of books sent to the American Philosophical Society through John Vaughan, Paris, April 26, 1816; 8-1/2x6-1/4, 4x6-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    A.D.S. 2p. and end. In French. Refers to Humboldt.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 12, 1816; 8-1/2x6-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications for the APS. Concerning a translation of his work. Refers to Correa de Serra, Mease, Wistar and Hassler.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 14, 1816; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S 3p. and add., end. In French. Has forwarded publications. Refers to Wistar and Correa de Serra.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 20, 1816; 10x8; LeRoy, Bayard & Co. (New York, N.Y.).
    New York, L. 1p. and end. Forwards package from Michaux.
  - Receipt to Jo[h]n Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 29, 1816; 9-3/4x8; LeRoy, Bayard & Co. (New York, N.Y.).
    New York, D. 1p. and end. For books received from F. A. Michaux.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 5, 1816; 10x8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. APS business. Refers to Warden, Gallatin and Correa de Serra.
  - List of books sent to John Vaughan for the APS, Sept. 17, 1816; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    A.D.S. 1p.
  - List of books sent to John Vaughan for the APS, Sept. 17, 1816; 9-1/2x7; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 18-20, 1816; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    FILM 199 FRAME 693
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Concerning publications for the APS. Refers to Warden, Hassler, Hosack, Jefferson and Z. Collins.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 28, 1816; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications. Refers to Hassler, Warden and Bartram.
  - Letter to J[o]hn Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 10, 1816; 10X8; Michaux, Francois André, 1770-1855